== srt字幕转制：accape.vicp.net ==
1884年四分之一的地球表面
都被大英帝国军队征服
能为女王和祖国奋战
是每位热血青年的无上光荣
不肯效命沙场的年轻人
将为亲友带来莫大耻辱
懦弱的象徵  ,  是一根 白色羽毛
《再战豪情》
Pass it left to Jack!
汤姆  ,  快传球
Pass the bloody thing, Tom!
传到左边给杰克
Tom, pass it left!
快传球呀
Pass the ball! Come on, Tom!
传到左边  快传球
To Jack!
快呀   传给杰克
Go on, Tom!
快呀  ,  汤姆
Tom!
汤姆  !
What's that man's name?!
搞什么 ? 太差了
You see the girls, Jack?
来吧  ,  杰克
Push on! Move it, boys! Come on!
往前冲  ,  冲啊
Stand tall!
守好  !
There you go  straight.
快去  ,  主教
Go on, Vicar!
传给崔屈
Sean! Sean!
崔屈
Go on  keep going!
继续上
住手  ,  不能少了你
Break it up!
别打了
I need you on the field, lad.
场上需要你   好吧
- Huh? - You're all right.
哈利 哈利  ,  右边  !
Behind you!
左边  !后面  !
Jack!
杰克
Take it, Jack!
快跑
Well done, old chap!
干得好 好汉
Well done, Jack.
干得好 杰克  ,
Is there anything else left in there?
还有什么比这更棒 ?
How long you going to be in that bathtub, Vicar?
你还要浸多久  ,  主教 ?
As long as I like.
看我心情
Stand tall, Vicar.
守好  !
Idiot!
白痴
Willoughby, you look wonderful, darling.
威洛毕  ,  你漂亮极了
Princess Willoughby.
威洛毕公主
Miss Willoughby.
威洛毕小姐
Hey, Tom, there's a hair out of place there, boy.
汤姆  ,  有一根没梳好
When are you gentlemen going to grow up?
你们这些绅士几时才会长大 ?
"Gentlemen"? Did he just call us "gentlemen"?
绅士 ? 他叫我们绅士 ?
I believe he did.
没错
- I won't take that from anyone. - Nor will I.
我可不能受这种侮辱  我也是
I like when you do this.
我喜欢你这样
Not my hair!
别碰的我头发
- Willoughby, this is  - Not the hair!
这样呢 ?    别碰我的头发  !
Not the hair!
别碰我的头发  !
And don't think we're going to take you any more seriously
等你升了官我们一样不搞你
once you're promoted, Miss Willoughby.
- We'll see about that. - Whoo!
等着瞧吧
Ladies.
女士们
Don't worry, Vicar, they're only women.
别紧张  ,  她们只是女人
They won't bite.
不会吃人
Just be quiet.
安静
Does it hurt?
会痛吗 ?
Uh  yes.
会啊
What are you two lovebirds laughing about?
你们小俩口 在笑什么 ?
His eye.
他的黑眼圈
Don't fall for it.
别傻了,
He colors it in with a pen.
那是画上去的
I can draw you one if you're feeling left out.
你要的话我也可以替你画
Go on, then.
好吧
What?
干嘛 ?
Well, I want a black eye like Jack's.
我要跟杰克一样有黑眼圈
If you really want one, Harry, I  can facilitate you.
你真要的话 我就打你
Want a second black eye, Jack?
还想挨打吗 ?
No.
不想
That's good.
真好
Are you nervous?
你紧张吗 ?
Stop it.
别这样
What?
怎样 ?
What are you two doing?
你们在干嘛 ?
Nothing.
没干嘛
I want to dance.
我想跳舞
N-Not up there, Ethne.
别上去  ,  艾瑟妮
Now, Ethne, come down from there, please.
快下来
Not until you dance with me, Harry.
除非你陪我跳舞  ,  费哈利
Oh, dear, yes, come down, Ethne.
艾瑟妮  ,  快下来
- For God's sake, be careful. - Oh, please.
天啊  !  小心点 --放心啦
Jack, tell her to get down.
杰克  ,  叫她下来
When does she ever listen to me?
她从来都不听我的
Ethne, listen to Jack, please.
艾瑟妮  ,  听杰克的话
Relax, Harry.
放心  ,  哈利
Listen to me.
听我的话
Thank you, Jack.
谢谢  ,  杰克
I will not pirouette.
我才不跳舞
Dance with me.
陪我跳舞
Right, right.
好吧  好吧
- Oh, my God. - Scary, isn't it, Harry?
天啊  !     很可怕吧  ,  哈利 ?
Don't be such a bore, Harry.
别这么古板嘛
I'm trying.
我没古板
Ooh! Ooh!
艾瑟妮
Please be careful, okay?
千万小心点
It's not very funny, Ethne.
不好笑
Excuse me, Mr. Faversham, sir.
抱歉费少爷  ,
Your father is asking for you and Miss Eustace.
令尊找您和艾小姐
Thank you.
谢谢
- Sir. - Sir.
爸  --长官
Colonel Sutch.
苏上校
Harry, my boy.
哈利  ,  好孩子
How are you, sir?
你好吗 ?   长官
Well, well. Mum.
好
Colonel Sutch.
你好   苏上校
I'm sorry to send for you, my dear.
抱歉把你找来  ,
I was hoping to steal you for the last dance.
想请你陪我跳舞
It'd be my pleasure, General.
我的荣幸  ,  将军
Your son won't dance with me.
你儿子不肯陪我跳
Where were you?
你跑到哪儿了?
Catching a breath of air, sir.
出去透透气
My dear.
来吧
She is very beautiful, Harry.
哈利  ,  她很美
Yes, she is, sir.
是的,  长官
I was thinking how proud my father would be
我爸在的话一定会很骄傲
if he were here.
An officer who gave his life for his country
一个为国捐躯的军人
deserves far more respect than I do.
比我更值得受尊敬
I wish I'd met him.
这我可以肯定
Are you ready, my dear?
你准备好了吗 ?
With all my heart.
全心全意
My lords, ladies and gentlemen, the general.
各位先生女士 费将军
Dr. Johnson once said
庄臣 曾经说过
every man feels meanly about himself
没当过兵就不算是男人
for not having been a soldier.
Well, that's something no one here tonight need fear.
但在座的男人都不必怕
Whether or not you've seen active service
不管你们有没有打过仗
you have shown yourselves willing to lay down your lives
都愿为国家抛头颅洒热血
and for that
我要向
I salute you.
你们致敬
- The Royal Cumbrians! - The Royal Cumbrians!
皇家坎布利军 皇家坎布利军  !
Now, in my mind, there is only one sacrifice more noble
我认为 有一种牺牲
than pledging one's life for one's country
比为国捐躯更伟大
and that is  loving
那就是为了 爱
and marrying a man who does.
毅然嫁给 一位军人
- Marry?! - Marry?!
嫁给
Harry  and Ethne.
敬哈利和艾瑟妮
Harry and Ethne!
敬哈利和艾瑟妮  !
Bravo!
太好了!
Bravo! Bravo!
Form a square!
布方阵  !
Well, now that we've had such a public engagement
既然我们都公开订婚了
can we have a nice, quiet wedding, please?
婚礼就别这么麻烦吧
Not on your life!
你想得美
I want the full works, the church near my home
我要盛大婚礼 在我家附近教堂举行
and then a rousing speech from your father.
再次听你爸激昂 的演说
My father?
我爸 ?
"I'd like to congratulate my son.
我儿子一点都不成材
When I was his age, I was in charge of a full regiment."
我在这年纪早就当团长了
He doesn't sound anything like that.
他没有这个意思
Oh, yes, he does.
他有
Besides, you will be in charge of a regiment.
你迟早都会当团长
Quiet!
安静
It'll be Jack and Isabelle's turn next.
杰克和伊莎贝也快好事近了
Jack? Oh, no, Jack will never get married.
杰克热爱军队  ,  才不会结婚
He's too much of a soldier.
你跟他一样
So are you.
我跟他不一样
Yes, but not like him.
才怪  ,
Yes, you are, more than him, more than any of them.
你比谁都热爱军队
You're my husband.
你是我丈夫
Good night, ladies
“晚安  ,  淑女们 ”
Go away.
滚开
Please, ignore them.
别理他们
Don't act like children!
别闹了
Merrily, we roll along, roll along, roll along
我们要纵情狂欢
Merrily, we roll along until the morning comes
直到通宵达旦
Good night, gentlemen, good night, gentlemen
晚安  ,  绅士
Good night, Ethne!
晚安  ,  艾瑟妮
Good night, Harry!
晚安  ,  哈利
Good night, Ethne, we have to take him home!
晚安  ,  艾瑟妮  ,  我们要押他归队
Come on, Harry, keep up!
加油  ,  跟上来
Come on, John!
来吧  ,  杰克
Come on, Mr. Castleton, get it out!
快点  ,  卡索顿  ,  快上啊
Mr. Trench, carry on!
崔屈  ,  宰了他
Mr. Castleton's dead  enemy spear through the foot!
卡索顿死了,  被敌人割喉
Come on, get a move on!
快走  ,  快走吧
Get it out!
出去
Come on, let's go! Come on!
动作快点
Gentlemen, the colonel!
各位  ,  上校来了
Gentlemen.
各位
I have some news.
我有新消息
An army of Muhammadan fanatics under the command
一支回教圣战份子组成的军队
of their self-proclaimed messiah, the Mahdi
在自称救世主的玛迪率领下
has attacked a British fortress in the Sudan.
攻击英军在苏丹阵地
Our forces there fought a heroic
我军英勇奋战
but in the end hopeless, rearguard action.
但仍寡不敌众
They were slaughtered to a man.
他们全都壮烈牺牲
As a result of these hostilities
由于敌众我寡
several regiments, including the Royal Cumbrians
有几支部队 包括皇家坎布利军
will be shipping out to the Sudan within the week.
将在一周内 被派到苏丹
Congratulations to you all.
恭喜各位  !
This government has finally seen fit
政府决定派
to send its soldiers to war.
皇家大军 出征
Finally, we're off.
终于能打仗了
Gentlemen.
各位
God has endowed
上帝透过
the British race
英国人
with a worldwide empire
建立的帝国
that they may execute
His sovereign purpose in the world.
在全世界执行上帝的旨意
The victories you will have over the heathen
当你们击溃那些异教徒
are the victories of the nobler soul in man.
将证明自己拥有更高贵的灵魂
- God save the queen. - God save the queen!
天佑女王 天佑女王
All together!
一起来
This is what nerves do to grown men.
等待是最紧张的时刻
If we're going to go to war, I wish we'd just get on with it.
要打仗的话就快点出发
Do you ever think about what it's going to be like
你可想过一旦
when we get there?
身陷战场 ?
All the time.
时常想  ,
Don't you?
你不会吗 ?
I sometimes wonder
我真不懂
what a godforsaken desert in the middle of nowhere
鸟不生蛋的沙漠
has to do with Her Majesty the queen.
跟女王有什么关系 ?
What's going on?What happened?
你是怎么了?
Aren't you afraid you won't come back?
你不怕回不来吗 ?
Did you have a bad dream about me or something?
你是梦到我出事吗 ?
Did I get my head lopped off by one of those Mahdi savages?
我是不是被野蛮人砍头 ?
Yes, Jack.
是啊  ,  杰克
Of course, I'm scared.
我当然害怕
Then, what
那么
what makes you go?
你为什么还要去 ?
I suppose  I'm going
我去
because you're going
因为 你也要去
you, Trench, Castleton, even Willoughby
你 、 崔屈  、  卡索顿  ,  还有威洛毕
but especially you.
但主要是因为你
There's no one I'd sooner trust my life with.
我可以把性命交给你
What is this?
这是什么 ?
My papers, sir.
我的呈文
If it's leave you want, there's a different procedure.
请假要用别的呈文
Normally I wouldn't consider it in the circumstances
通常我不会批准
but given that you've just got engaged
但因你刚订婚
It isn't leave I want, sir.
我不想请假
I wish to resign my commission.
我想辞去军职
If I were you, I'd think very carefully
如果我是你
about what you're saying, Lieutenant.
就会慎重考虑
I've made up my mind, sir.
我去意已决
We'll talk about this when you've spoken with your father.
先跟你父亲谈过再说
It isn't his decision, sir.
他不能替我作主
I do not accept these papers, Lieutenant
我拒绝这份辞呈
and I do not accept that one of my men
下周我们就要 出征了
would walk out on his regiment
我绝不允许部下临阵退缩
- Sir   the very week
长官 这个礼拜
we are shipping off to war!
我们即将奔赴战场
Now, as far as I'm concerned, you were never here.
我就当你没来过
You can thank your father for that.
这是看在你爸的面子
Sir
长官
I wish to resign my commission.
我要辞去军职
Please leave these barracks immediately.
请你立刻滚出军营
Hello, Miss Willoughby!
威洛毕小姐
I thought I could smell
难怪我闻到玫瑰花香
the scent of fresh roses in the air.
Harry's resigned.
哈利辞职了
Resigned what?
辞什么职 ?
His bloody commission, what do you think?
他辞去军职
What did Hamilton do?
汉密顿做了什么 ?
Refuse him leave to marry Ethne?
不肯批假让他结婚吗 ?
Hamilton didn't do anything.
不是
There was no excuse for it.
哈利是临阵退缩  临阵退缩 ?
"Excuse for it"?
临阵退缩 ?
You're talking about Harry.
你在说哈利
He's right, Tom. He's just got engaged.
他说的对 他才刚订婚  ,
It's perfectly natural to have doubts.
当然会有点疑虑
We're sent to war, and the very next day he resigns?
我们马上就要上战场
There's no doubt about it.
这还有什么好说 ?
What's that supposed to mean?
是什么意思 ?
I think it's perfectly clear what it means.
我的意思很明 白
- Tom, don't be absurd. - Shut up, Vicar.
别乱讲话 --闭嘴
It means he's a coward, Jack.
他是个懦夫
Then say that to his face.
有种就当着他的面说
I would've done
我本来也想
only he left the barracks before I had a chance.
可惜他早就溜之大吉
All right, then, say it to my face.
好吧 当着我的面说
Easy, Jack.
别冲动  ,  杰克
Harry's a disgrace!
哈利是个耻辱
He's disgraced the regiment!
他让整个部队蒙羞
Jack!
杰克  !
He's the best soldier in the regiment!
他是最顶尖的军人
Obviously not when it counts.
一开战就落荒而逃
Get off!
放开我
I will tell him
我会告诉他的
but not to his face  he doesn't deserve it.
但我不屑当面跟他说
He deserves to be treated
他瞧不起我们  ,
with the same contempt that he treated us.
我要让他难看
What contempt?
你在说什么 ?
Did he talk to you about it?
有跟你们说过吗 ?
Did he talk to any of you?
他事先有跟你们说过吗 ?
He's left our backs exposed
他临阵逃脱却不敢告诉我们
and he doesn't even have the courage to tell us.
He was my friend, too, Jack.
他也曾是我的朋友
He'll be there.
他一定会去
This has to be answered.
他要付 出代价
Do you, Harry Faversham
你愿意
take this woman to be your lawful, wedded wife?
娶这位女子成为你合法妻子吗 ?
Yes, and you may kiss the bride.
愿意  ,  可以亲吻新娘了
You can't jump ahead like that.
别猴急嘛  ,
You have to let me enjoy my wedding.
先让我享受婚礼的喜悦
It's your fault we won't be able
你害我们要等半年才能成亲
to do the real one for another six months.
There's no reason why we can't get married
我们随时都可以结婚
whenever we like, is there?
I've heard that before.
别哄我了
I've left the army.
我离开部队了
No, Ethne, I  I have  left the army.
是真的,  艾瑟妮 我辞去军职
Why?
为什么 ?
Well, there was talk they may send us abroad
我们可能被派到海外
for a year or two.
也许要去一  、  两年
I didn't want to wait that long to get married.
我不想等这么久才结婚
Well, I would've waited
我愿意等你
or come with you.
或是跟你一起去
My mother did the same for my father.
我妈就是这样做
Yes, I know, but it isn't what I wanted for us.
我知道  ,  但我不想这样
You're all that matters to me now.
现在你对我最重要
Where were they going to send you?
你们要被派到哪里 ?
They weren't sure.
还未确定
Mr. Faversham.
费先生
Is this your friends' idea of a joke?
这是你死党的恶作剧吗 ?
What is it, Harry?
这是什么 ?
Feathers of  of cowardice.
代表懦弱的羽毛
Yesterday, we  were informed
昨天
that our regiment would be shipping out
我们得知军队要派往苏丹
to the Sudan
that we would be  sent to war.
就要上 战场打仗
You don't know where they were sending you
你还说不知道要被派到哪儿
you said so yourself  and you did it for me.
这都是为了我
- Ethne  - Nobody in their right minds
艾瑟妮 --没有人能说你是懦夫
could call you a coward, especially not your friends.
尤其是你的好友
There's been some kind of misunderstanding.
这是误会  ,
You have to clear it up.
你要向他们解释
You have to go back to the regiment and clear it up.
你一定要归队
No, I can't.
我办不到
Then I will.
那我去
I'll go see Trent, Willoughby and Castleton myself
我去找崔屈  、 威洛毕和卡索顿
and tell them it's my fault you resigned
说你是为了我
that you did it for me.
才这么做
It has nothing to do with you, Ethne!
我并不是为了你
Then why?
那是为什么 ?
I never wanted to join the army!
我从来就不想从军
I did it for my father.
这全是为了我爸
I thought I'd serve out my commission
我只想当一  、  两年兵
in a year or two
keep everyone happy, and then I could just
让大家高兴  ,  然后再
You'd what, wait till we were married to tell me the truth?
怎样 ? 结了婚才跟我说吗 ?
No, Ethne, l-I never meant to lie to you.
我不是故意要欺骗你
No, but you were quite happy to let me deceive myself.
但是你却让我相信
Do you think people will let us forget this?
你以为众人会放过我们吗 ?
I don't care what people think, Ethne.
我不在乎别人怎么想
All I care about is us.
我只在乎我们俩
It's not about us, Harry.
原本只是我们的事
It's not just about us.
不过现在却不同
What about Jack?
杰克愿把性命交给你
He would give his life for you.
Don't you think I know that?
你以为我不知吗 ?
Then go back.
那就归队吧
It's not too late.
还来得及
Tell them you wouldn't have resigned
告诉他们是为了我才退出
if it weren't for me.
I would  have resigned
我还是会辞职
and I wouldn't have gone to war for anything or anyone.
我不会为任何人任何事 打仗
Then you are a coward.
那你 就是懦夫
Fight for England!
为祖国奋战
"Avoid drinking local water and spirits
别喝当地的水和酒
"avoid local barrooms and brothels
别到当地的酒吧和妓院
and, above all, remember, you're a Christian soldier."
牢记你们都是基督徒
Why'd they give this to me?
他们给我这个干嘛 ?
It must be for you, Vicar.
一定是给你的
Father?
父亲
After you.
您先请
May I speak with you, sir?
我想跟你谈谈
I don't know you.
我不认识你
I need to speak with you, sir.
我必须跟你谈谈
British attack the City of Korti!
英军占领玛迪的城市
British casualties in the Sudan!
英军在苏丹伤亡惨重
苏丹战事英军死伤名单
Something wrong, Jack?
杰克  ,  怎么了?
Well, I don't know about you lot
我要在狙击手开枪前喝一杯
but I'm going to get a drink before Mustafa does.
It's probably poisoned.
可能下了毒
Mustafa, after you, mate.
穆斯塔法  ,  你先喝
- Take cover! - Stay down!
狙击手  !隐蔽
Take cover! Take cover!
快找掩护  !
Where is he?
在哪
Get down and stay down!
快趴下来  ,  趴下来
- Get down! - Take cover!
Where is he?
找他们
他们在哪儿 ?
Take cover!
快趴下
Stay down! Stay down, everyone!
快趴下 都趴下
Find him! Find him! Where the bloody hell is he?
找 都去找 他们在哪儿 ?
He's on the roof!
他在高处
- Where?! - Over there!
哪 --那里
Over there!
在那里
Get him!
拿下
Now!
现在
- Move! - Right, sir.
女人  !
Put the gun down.
放下枪  !
Put the gun down!
Tell him to put the gun down!
叫他把枪放下
Put your gun down!
把你的枪放下来
For God sakes, man, put your gun down!
我警告你  ,  放下枪
Don't.
不要
Hold your fire.
别开枪
Put the gun down.
放下枪
Tell him to put his gun down!
叫他把枪放下
Don't! Don't! Don't!
不要  ,  别开枪
What's done is done, Harry.
别再去想了
No, sir
不行
it isn't.
发生这种事
Something like this happens
and you're lost.
你一定会感到迷惘
You don't know
你会怀疑自己的勇气
who you are anymore or what you're capable of.
Unless I do something
除非我有一番作为
this is how people will always remember me
否则 人们对我的记忆就是
a feather
一根羽毛
and that is how I will always see myself
我也会如此看我自己
a coward.
一个懦夫
All I know is I can't live with myself like this.
我不能接受这样的我
Who gave you the fourth feather?
第四根羽毛 是谁给的?
Jack Durrance?
杰克吗 ?
No, sir.
不
Ethne did.
是艾瑟妮
Dearest Ethne:
亲爱 的艾瑟妮
Forgive me for all the shame I've caused you.
请原谅我为你带来耻辱
I can only imagine the indignities
你一定因我受到很多委屈
you must have suffered because of me.
苏丹
I hope my leaving London will at least allow you
希望我的离开能让你重生
to begin your life again, free of my shadow.
摆脱我的阴影
I have no right to your trust or claim to your love
我无权获得你的信任和爱
but please believe, I never set out to deceive you.
但请相信我无意欺骗你
I don't know
我不知能否弥补我的过错
if an opportunity will ever arise to redeem myself
but I have to believe it will
但我必须有信心
and I have to believe
我深信这次我将面对恐惧
that this time I'll face up to my fears
and prove to myself and others, I'm not a coward.
向自己和世人证明 我并非懦夫
What did he pay you to bring him here?
他付了多少钱才来这儿 ?
Listen, Gustave, I wouldn't bring
听住  ,  我才不肯
Take this.
拿去
Now get out.
滚出去
Don't come back.
别再回来
What do you want?
你要什么 ?
Can you take me to the British camp at Korti?
你能带我到英军阵地吗 ?
Across the desert?
横越沙漠 ?
Yes.
对
Why?
为什么 ?
Can you take me there or not?
你到底能不能 ?
For your time.
你的酬劳
Can you speak Arabic?
你会说阿拉伯话吗 ?
I can learn.
我可以学
Yes, but can you learn to look like an Arab?
你必须假扮成阿拉伯人
If the Mahdi's men find you
否则会被敌人发现
I'm taking a caravan of whores up to Korti next week.
下周我要带妓女到科提
Come and see me then.
到时再来找我
Left, right, left, right, left, right, left.
英军科提营地 左右  、 左右
Thank you.
谢谢
Left, right, left, right, left, right, left.
左右  、 左右
Congratulations, Jack.
恭喜  ,  我决定让你放几星期假
I've decided to give you a few weeks' leave.
Every report I receive singles you out for praise.
每份报告都在表扬你
You and several other officers will be going to London
你跟几名军官先回伦敦
to convince Parliament
争取国会和舆论的支持
and the public opinion that it's high time
我们到科提营救戈登将军
this government ordered us out of Korti
to rescue General Gordon.
是一项艰巨任务
With your permission, I'd rather stay here with the regiment.
请你准许我留下来
Why?
为什么 ?
I don't feel I've done my duty yet.
我还没上战场打仗
I wouldn't want to let the others down.
我不想让同胞失望
Permission refused.
请求拒绝
Sir, why me?
为什么是我 ?
Because you're a hero, Jack.
因为你是个英雄
With all due respect, sir
请恕我直言
I don't think we've been fighting long enough
这场仗  ,  造就不了英雄
to have any heroes in this campaign.
Shut up!
闭嘴  ,
Keep them quiet, Saadi! What do I pay you for?!
叫她们闭嘴 你这没用的东西
They are princesses.
她们是公主
Can you imagine
你可以想像得到吗 ?
even the savages have royalty?
连野蛮人也有分贵贱
But the British soldiers
英国士兵每人付三块钱
pay me three dirham an hour for them.
Well worth the trip to Korti.
去一趟科提真好赚
Is this the Mahdi's territory?
这是玛迪的地盘吗 ?
Everywhere is Mahdi territory.
到处都是玛迪的地盘
What is it?
怎么 ?
She doesn't like my manners?
她对我不满吗 ?
Savage!
闭嘴  !
Stop it!
住手  !
You're not to look at me!
我叫你别看我  !
Stop!
住手  !
Stop doing this!
不要这样对我说话  !
Stop it! Stop it!
放下来  !
Stop it!
快住手  !
I'll teach you manners!
我要给你点教训  !
Stop it! Enough!
快住手  !     够了!
That'll teach you manners!
我要教训你  !
Enough!
够了!
You think she'll thank you for what you did today?
你以为她会感激你 ?
I don't expect her to.
我并不这么想
Of course you do; you saved her life.
你当然想 你救了她一命
Tsk, tsk! Tsk!
过来
They're like children.
她们就像小孩子
They have no concept of gratitude or loyalty.
不明 白 什么是感恩或忠诚
That's something you British don't understand.
你们英国人什么都不懂
You come here, trying to civilize them
还想用
with your Christian values.
基督教感化他们
Now, she'll thank you.
现在 她会感激你
Don't be so proud, my friend.
别这么自以为是
Let him be!
放过他
There are followers of the Mahdi everywhere in the Sudan.
苏丹到处都有玛迪的追随者
The rebel tribes are gathering forces under the leadership
玛迪率领圣战份子
of the Mahdi to fight us.
发动叛乱
We do not need more reinforcements.
我们不需要支援兵力
All we need is for this government
只需要政府下令全力进攻
to give an order to march
就能一举歼灭敌人
and we will route the enemy
and preserve the dignity of our empire.
捍卫大英帝国霸权
Have you heard from Harry?
你有哈利的消息吗 ?
No.
没有
Have you?
你呢 ?
No.
没有
Ethne, you can't blame yourself.
艾瑟妮  ,  别怪你自己
You make a stupid mistake
犯了错就得永远承担后果
and you pay for it for the rest of your life.
I can't forgive myself.
我不能原谅自己
You had your reasons.
你有你的苦衷
What reasons?
什么苦衷 ?
Pride?
自尊心吗 ?
Because I was afraid of what people would say.
我担心别人看不起我 ?
What do I care what people said?
我为何在乎别人的想法 ?
I loved him.
我爱他
Ethne, you have to
艾瑟妮  ,  你要
He came to me, Jack.
他来找我
He came to me and I turned him away.
我却狠心拒绝他
It's all right.
没事了
It won't be like this for the rest of your life.
你不会悔恨终生
I'll write to you when I'm gone.
我会写信给你
Left, right, left, right, left, right, left.
左右  、 左右
Left, right, left, right, left, right, left, right
left, right, stop!
左右  、 左右
Referee, come on!
拜托  ,
That wasn't fair!
这不公平 这是什么 ?
Congratulations!
祝贺
Open up.
张开嘴
He's got no teeth. Get rid of him.
他没牙齿  ,  赶走他
Who's next?!
继续来
Come on, keep 'em coming, keep 'em coming.
再来一次
No, he's too small.
不行  ,  他太小了
I want to see this man's teeth.
我要看他的牙齿
He looks strong enough.
他挺壮的,  让他提行李
Put him with the baggage porters.
How many more we got? How many, Bill?
我们有多少人
Okay, we need another three of them.
还得要3个
What's going on?!
怎么回事 ?
This man comes from a tribe of slaves.
他来自奴隶部落
The men will not serve with him, sir.
大家不肯跟他共事
Look, we need all the help we can get.
我们的人手不够
Baggage porter!
让他提行李
Get him through.
快带下去
I can't believe it.
不可思议
Come on. Come on. Get him through.
快带他去干活
Come on, next.
下一个
My Dearest Jack:
亲爱 的杰克
I was so relieved to receive your last letter.
很高兴收到你的来信
While the whole country is celebrating
举国正欢庆你们的战役
your campaign against the Mahdi
all I feel is dread and all I think about are
我却 内心惶恐
the precious times we spent together: you, Harry, and I.
想到你 、  哈利和我相聚的时光
My father used to say
我父亲曾说  ：
that God takes away what's dearest to our hearts
上帝夺走我们的
to remind us how much we take for granted.
挚爱  ,  提醒我们他们有多重要
Now that it's too late, I wish I could turn back time.
但太迟了,  真希望时光倒流
How differently I'd do things given a second chance.
让我不再重蹈覆辙
Take good care of yourself, Jack.
你要好好保重
I don't mind if you don't come back covered in glory.
你不一定要立战功回来
Just come back safely.
只要平安归来就好
Your friend forever, Ethne.
你永远的朋友 艾瑟妮
Thoughtful of General Wolseley
伍将军真体帖给我们这些阳伞
to give us these umbrellas, eh, Vicar?
I burn in the sun.
我快被烤焦了
Come on, now, faster!
加油 快
Faster!
快
Watch out!
注意
He sits alone. Have you seen him before?
他都一个人  ,  你看过他吗 ?
Who are you?
你是谁 ?
We are watching you
我们在看着你
Abou Fatma.
阿布法玛
My name is Abou Fatma.
我叫阿布法玛
Vedu.
班度
I was a scout for General Hicks.
我曾是席将军的斥候  阿拉伯话
l know you're English!
我知道你是英国人
There are many in this camp who serve the Mahdi.
这儿有很多玛迪的追随者
When they find out there's a British spy amongst them
要是他们发现这儿有英军间谍
watching them, they'll kill him.
就会杀了他
It won't be long, Vedu.
你等着瞧吧  ,  班度
Why would you warn me?
你为什么要警告我 ?
For money.
为了钱
I can't pay you.
我没有钱
What's the feather for?
那根羽毛代表什么 ?
First time I killed a man.
代表我第一次杀人
Five men.
我杀过五个人
Wait.
等等
Ten men.
十个人
This
这
I will wear soon.
我很快就会戴上这个
I'm a good soldier.
我是个好战士
I  will protect you.
我会保护你
Who did this?! Who did this?!
这是谁干的?是谁干的?
Who did this?!
到底是谁干的?
Keep your eyes to the front.
向前转
Why would a British spy be hiding from his own soldiers?
英军间谍为什么躲避自己人 ?
I'm not a spy.
我不是间谍
Is that the same letter you read over and over again
你是一直看同一封信
or do you get a different one each day?
还是每天都收到一封信 ?
He writes them to himself.
都是他自己写的
Read us a line.
念一句来听听
Read your own.
念你自己的
Don't be so coy.
别怕羞
You're amongst friends.
大家都是朋友
Come on, Jack, you can trust us.
来嘛  ,  你能信任我们
"I'm so glad I came to hear you speak that day in London."
很高兴那天在伦敦听你演讲
Come on, more than that.
别这样   多念几句嘛
Don't leave us hanging on  elaborate.
e凉下我们
"It made me realize how much your friendship means to me.
我发现你的友情对我有多重要
"Come back safely and soon
请赶快平安归来
my dearest Jack."
亲爱 的杰克
Well, well done, "my dearest Jack"!
太好了,  杰克
Who's the lucky lady?
幸运的女孩是谁 ?
Ethne.
艾瑟妮
I'm going to ask her to marry me.
我要向她求婚
Congratulations, Jack.
恭喜了,  杰克
That's fantastic, Jack.
太好了
She hasn't said yes.
她还没答应
Aah, she will.
她会的
"I realize how much I bloody love you."
我发现我有多爱你
"How much your friendship means to me."
你的友情对我有多重要
Same thing.
一样啦
Cheers, Jack.
干杯
Congratulations, Jack.
恭喜  ,  杰克
They look like the Mahdi's men.
他们像是玛迪的手下
I need to find out where he's going.
我要查出他去哪里
Deserters, sir.
这很紧急
Corporal, cease fire!
别开火
Harry.
哈利 ?
Looks like they've stopped for the night.
他们晚上停下来
Why is it so important to follow them?
你为什么要跟踪他们 ?
The Mahdi spies will report on our troop movements.
玛迪的探子会报告英军行动
Not the spies
我说的不是探子
your friends.
是你的朋友
To help them  if I can.
如有机会我想帮助他们
Are you a deserter?
你是逃兵吗 ?
Something like that.
算是吧
I was sent to fight, and I ran away.
我被派去打仗却临阵退缩
Why?
为什么 ?
Well
我
I just
我只是
There are many reasons why.
有很多原因
Mostly, I was afraid.
主要是我很害怕
I found you half dead
你独自横越沙漠
crossing the desert alone.
差点没命
You say you are afraid?
还说你会害怕 ?
It's a different kind of fear.
那是不同 的恐惧
Why are you protecting me?
你为什么要保护我 ?
God put you in my way.
上帝的旨意  ,
I have no choice.
我别无选择
God?
上帝 ?
An Englishman and a Christian.
他要你保护英国人 和基督徒 ?
You must've done something terrible to offend him.
你一定干了坏事触怒他
You laugh like an Englishman.
你笑起来像英国人
And how does an Englishman laugh?
英国人是怎样笑的?
Abou
阿布
they're leaving!
他们要走了
They're getting away.
他们溜了
We can't lose them.
不能跟丢
All right, I'll
好吧
I'll just sit here and wait for you.
我就坐着等你
Take your time.
慢慢来
That is the fortress of Abou Clea.
那是阿布克里堡
The British reinforcements are stationed there.
英国援军阵地
Why would the spies be going to a British fort?
敌人的探子怎么会去那儿 ?
The fort has been taken over by the Mahdi's army.
玛迪的军队攻下这座碉堡
But this is where our troops are heading.
英军就是要来这儿
Abou!
阿布
Abou, warn my friends.
阿布  ,  去警告我的朋友
Wear this!
穿这个  !
Company, halt!
停下来  !
- Company, halt! - Company, halt!
停下来  !天啊 崔屈  !
Mr. Trench!
崔屈  !
William!
威廉  !
Get away from them!
快滚开  ,  这些肮脏鬼
Leave them alone!
离他们远一点
You filthy
这群野兽
Sir?
长官 ?
You leave these bloody men alone!
让他们自己呆着
Come back here!
回来
Go on!
继续  !
Sir.
长官
The Egyptians have captured an enemy scout.
埃及人捉到敌人的探子
Where did you find this man?
在哪儿找到的?
I came to you myself.
我是自愿来的
The Mahdi's men have captured your fort at Abou Clea.
玛迪攻占了阿布克里堡
This man is lying, sir.
他在说谎
He's the one who stole the camels
他偷走骆驼
They will attack you here!
他们会偷袭你们
Tell him a British garrison would never fall
英军阵地绝不会被野蛮人拿下
to the Mahdi savages!
Ask him if he knows the penalty for being a spy.
他知不知道当间谍的惩罚 ?
I'm not a spy.
我不是间谍
The Mahdi's men have left these bodies to keep you here.
玛迪手下故意把你们引 在这儿
Tell him I'll bury him alive if he speaks another word
他再说英文我就把他活埋
of English!
Ask him who sent him here and why.
他到底是谁派来的?
He says a British officer sent him, sir.
他说是一个英国军官
A general, no doubt.
说不定是将军呢  ,
What was his name?
他叫什么 ?
Come here, son.
我过来  ,
I'll show you a British officer.
什么英国军官 ?
This is a British officer!
这才是英国军官
And this  is a British officer's blood.
这是英国军官的鲜血
Now lick it up  every bloody drop!
给我把每滴血都舔干净
Look! Don't be rash!
别这么冲动
Take him away.
把他带下  ,
Find out why the enemy sent him.
用任何手段查出动机
Use any means necessary.
回教徒都会埋葬死人
The Muslims always bury their dead, even the enemy dead.
就连敌人也一样
These bodies have been left here for a reason!
尸体留在这里必有诈
Come on, you!
给我来吧
Look, I think you should tell Hamilton.
我们应该报告汉密顿上校
I agree, Tom.
我同意
What for?
为什么 ?
As a precaution, Tom.
以防万一
This man was trying to mislead us.
这个人想误导我们
I've made my decision.
我做了决定
I'm not going to waste the colonel's time
我不会浪费上校的时间
by sending some half-naked savage
让他听野蛮人的鬼话
in front of him with a tall tale.
What is it, Jack?
怎么了?
There's something up.
有发现
Thou God, who reigneth over all the earth
神啊 您统驭宇宙万物
who art the Lord of all our salvation
您是我们的救主
give your ear unto my prayer.
请听我的祷告
For Thou art greater than the common man.
您比凡人伟大
Everything is as you wish it.
凡事都是您的安排
Everything is as you will it.
人人皆听您的旨意
If what we're doing is just
我们的行为 若光明正大
then give us the strength to serve you
请赐我们力量伸张正义
for that which I greatly feared has come upon me
为我的心中充满恐惧
and that which I was afraid of is come unto me.
深怕我的恐惧即将成真
Form a line.
列队   第一连列队
First company  a section, if you please.
One section will fix bayonets.
第一排  ,  拿出刺刀
Fix!
上刺刀
Ready!
预备
Present!
举枪  !
- Fire. - Fire.
开火  !
Fire!
Reload!
装弹
100 yards!
一百码
Present!
举枪  !
They're not armed, sir.
他们手无寸铁
- Fire. - Fire.
开火  !
Fire!
What in God's name are they doing?
他们到底在做什么 ?
Present!
举枪  !
- Fire. - Fire.
开火  !
Fire!
50 yards!
五十码  !
Present!
举枪  !
- Fire. - Fire.
开火  !
Fire!
Thank you, Mr. Willoughby.
谢谢你  ,  威洛毕
Thank you, Sergeant.
谢谢你
Order  up!
持枪立正  !
Soldier  arm!
枪上肩  !
Left turn.
向左转  !
Left, right, left!
齐步走
- Form square! - Form square!
布阵  !   排成方阵 列队  !
Form square!
列队  !
Bring over those camels! Line them up!
动作快点  !列队  !
Quickly now, take positions!
动作快点  !
Number Three Section, fall in!
全连列队  !
Steady.
稳着
Steady, boys, steady!
Be calm.
冷静
Nice and calm.
冷静点
Be nice and calm.
Battalion prepare the cavalry, Mr. Willoughby.
骑兵出动预备
Battalion, prepare the cavalry.
骑兵进攻预备
Make way for the cavalry!
进攻预备
Number One Company, prepare for volley.
第一连开火预备
Number One Company, two rounds volley fire!
第一连连续开火预备
Number One Company
第一连
two rounds volley fire!
连续开火预备
Steady on the right, Mr. Castleton!
举枪  !
Pick your targets!
瞄准  !
Fire!
开火  !
守住了!
第二连进攻预备
Sir, we're being attacked from behind, sir!
敌人从后方攻击
Close in on the right, Castleton!
右翼迎敌预备
Officers to the front!
军官到阵前
Present
就位  !
aim
举枪  !
Castleton!
卡索顿  !
fire!
开火  !
Fire!
Keep your horses a target!
瞄准  !
Hold this line!
守住
The British Cavalry, sir!
英军骑兵队来了
They're retreating!
他们撤退了
They're running!
他们跑了
All right, men, cease fire!
停火  !
Cease fire!
Congratulations, sir.
恭喜  ,  长官
Battle's not over yet.
这场仗还没打完
Yes!
啊
We sod 'em off, lads!
我们击退了他们
Send out the skirmishers, Mr. Willoughby.
散兵追击  !
Send out the skirmishers!
Well done, Four Section!
好样的
Vicar!
汤姆  !
Come on, Vicar!
来呀  ,  主教
Vicar, come on!
- Close the square! - Close the square!
快回去  !
Charge!
保持方阵队形
Deliver me from blood guiltiness, O God.
神啊  ,  原谅我大开杀戒
It's not the British! It's the Mahdi!
那不是友军  ,  那是敌军
Get back!
不  !快回去
Volley fire, if you please, Mr. Willoughby!
二十五步
The skirmishers, sir?
他们是散兵
Hold this square at all costs
你一定要死守方阵
Get back to the square! Get back to the square!
快回到方阵 快回去呀  !
Get back to the square! Go!
快回去呀  !
Get back to the square! Go! Go!
Vicar!
主教
my sins deliver before me!
我们不能丢下他们
Volley fire, Mr. Willoughby!
全力 开火
Now!
Mr. Willoughby, I gave you a direct order!
我直接命令你
Castleton!
卡索顿
Save me from my sins!
Vicar, get back to the four square!
主教  !     卡索顿  ,  快回来
- Go on, Trench! Go on! - Run!
快跑  !
Present!
举枪  !
Fire!
开火  !
Don't shoot!
别开枪
Come on! Let's go!
快走
Vicar!
主教  !
Close the square!
守住方阵  !
Mr. Willoughby
威洛毕先生  !
Jack!
杰克  !
What are your orders, sir?
你的指令是什么 ?
Sir!
长官 ?
Sound the retreat!
全面撤退  !
"My dear Jack "
亲爱 的杰克
谢谢你告诉我
I'm a fool.
我真蠢
I was a fool to think that I could ever go back home.
居然以为 我可以回家
I can't.
我回不去了
Your friend needs help.
你的朋友需要帮助
My friend knows how to help himself.
他会自己想办法
I can't see.
我看不见
I can't see!
我看不见了
Oh! Don't!
我看不
Don't! Don't! Don't!
我不行
Who are you?
你是谁 ?
I have letters.
我的信呢 ?
Who are you?
你是谁 ?
I can't see. I can't see.
我看不见
I can't see.
Hello, Jack.
你好  ,  杰克
Ethne.
艾瑟妮
How are you?
你好吗 ?
I wanted to ask your advice, General.
我想问你的意见
My advice?
我的意见 ?
Jack Durrance has
杰克
has asked me to marry him.
向我求婚
You don't need my advice.
你不必问我
Jack Durrance is a good man.
他是个好人
I haven't answered him yet.
我还没答应
I was wondering if you'd heard from Harry.
你有没有哈利的消息 ?
I've heard nothing
没有
and, uh
再说
I don't think I shall hear from him again.
我不会再有他的消息了
I should've listened.
我应该听他说的话
I miss him.
我很挂念他
My son loved Jack Durrance like a brother.
我儿子和杰克情同手足
I know he'd want you to be happy.
他也希望你得到幸福
A few more weeks and he'll be able to ride without help.
过几个星期他就能自己骑马
Will that be the end of your penance?
你的忏悔圣事就结束吗 ?
Jack.
杰克
Not bad.
不错嘛
You should see me on a camel.
你应该看我骑骆驼
Lavender
薰衣草
and onions.
和洋葱
Sunday lunch.
周日 午餐
Take the horse to the stables and you can have some.
把马牵回马厩
Thank you, Robert, it's quite all right.
谢谢你  ,  没关系
It's me, Jack.
杰克  ,  是我
Tom.
汤姆
They finally made you captain, Miss Willoughby.
他们终于升你为上尉
All those decorations.
你有那么多奖章
You must have a few, yourself.
你也拿了不少
How'd you know I was visiting today?
你怎么知道我会来 ?
l, uh
我
I saw Harry, Jack.
我看到哈利
Where?
在哪儿 ?
In the Sudan.
在苏丹
I was following our retreat.
我跟大家一起撤退
We had a terrible time of it.
我们死伤惨重
The enemy hounded us all the way.
敌人紧盯不放
The desert itself seemed to side with them.
沙漠一片死寂
We ran out of water, medical supplies
饮水和药物都耗尽
even had to leave stragglers behind.
我们甚至要丢下伤兵
Finally, our own native scouts turned on us.
最后连当地斥候都叛变
We lost more men on that retreat than we did at the battle.
那次撤退比那场血战更惨烈
Get out!
滚出去
Didn't you hear what I said?
听到吗 ?
I said get out or I'll have you whipped
我叫你滚
you filthy wog!
要不然我就要鞭打你
Like you had my friend whipped?
就像你鞭打我的朋友 ?
Harry?
哈利 ?
I sent a man to warn you
我请人来警告你
and you had him tortured for his pains.
你却把他打到不似人形
I
我
What would it have cost to listen?
你为什么不肯听 ?
I didn't know it was you.
我不知道是你派来的
You should've taken precautions, Tom.
你应该小心谨慎
I didn't know it was you.
我不知道是你派来的
For God's sake, what are you doing here?
你跑来这儿干嘛 ?
And afterwards?
后来呢 ?
He, uh  he asked me for some money and left.
他 他向我要些钱就走了
To come back?
为了回英国 ?
No.
不是
No, there was a  there was a rumor going around
谣传说 有些官兵成为俘虏
that some of our surviving soldiers
有些官兵成为俘虏
had been captured and taken to prison.
Harry thought Trench might be one of them.
哈利相信崔屈也被俘
He went after him?
他想去救他吗 ?
I tried to stop him, Jack.
我尝试阻止他
I told him they were only rumors
我说那只是谣传
that the chances of survival were  virtually none.
他们根本活不了
He wouldn't listen.
但是他不肯听
Did you come here to tell Ethne Harry was dead?
你是来跟艾瑟妮说 哈利死了?
I don't know that he's dead, Jack.
他生死未  卜
So you've come to give her hope?
你是来给她希望 ?
What would you do in my place?
如果是你会怎么做 ?
Keep it to myself, Tom, until I was sure.
什么也别说 除非你确定
And the Mahdi said to the British prisoners：
玛迪跟英军俘虏说
“God had punished you for pride ”
上帝惩罚你们的自大
“ for he is mightier than all your armies.”
他比你们的军队更强大
“So he sent them to the great prison of Omdurman.”
他把他们关进死牢
“ to await their deaths.”
让他们等死
What did he say?
他说什么 ?
Your friend is dead.
你朋友死了我看到崔屈被活捉
I saw Trench taken alive.
Prisoners were taken to Omdurman last month.
俘虏上个月 被关进大牢
Your army abandoned them.
你的军队抛弃他们
The shame is no longer yours.
这不再是你的错
You're responsible to yourself and to God
你要对自己和上帝负责
not to them.
不是对他们
I am responsible to my friend.
我对朋友负责
I will find him.
我要找到他
You have learned nothing.
别傻了,
You've done enough.
你做的够多了
It's never enough, Abou.
永远都不够
Look, if the Mahdi's men find out I'm British
他们发现我是英国人
they'll take me to their prison.
一定会把我关起来
It's the only way I'll find my friend.
我就能找到我的朋友
They will hang you.
他们会把你吊死
Abou, you must help me get into the prison.
你一定要帮我混进大牢
I will not be responsible for your death.
我不能让你 白 白送死
How could you be responsible for my death?
你凭什么管我生死 ?
I will die if it is God's will.
我死了也是上帝的旨意
Yes?
是吗 ?
You English walk too proudly on the earth.
你们英国人太自大了
You are a fool
你是个傻子
my friend.
我的朋友
Trench!
崔屈  !
Ibrahim!
亚伯罕  !
Trench!
干嘛 ?
Don't lose our space!
占好我们的地方
Come on, son.
来吧  ,
You mustn't fall.
你不能倒下去
别倒下去
All right
好吗 ?
Harry?
哈利 ?
Harry
哈利
if you didn't come with the army, then who sent you?
你没跟着军队 为什么会来 ?
You did.
为了你
All this way  for a feather.
就为了一根小小的羽毛
I brought some money.
我有些钱
How much?
多少 ?
A hundred.
一百块
Hundred?
一百块 ?
Only food allowed. All parcels must be opened!
只能带食物  ,  袋子都要打开
What's going on?
怎么回事 ?
Who are those women?
她们是谁 ?
They're all relatives of the men in here.
囚犯的家属
They bring them scraps of food.
她们带食物来
Let's see if we can get you something to eat.
我们去找点食物
What can we do with this money?
这些钱能够怎样用?
Well, there's no chance of bribing Idris.
不可能收买阿达斯
His entire family was wiped out by one of our artillery attacks.
他全家都被英军炮兵打死
Now, Hassan, on the other hand, is infinitely corruptible.
另 一方面  ,  哈森 却很贪心
For 100 dirhams, he'll either help us escape
他不会为一百块帮我们
or he'll stab us in the back and keep the money.
会拿了钱又杀了我们
I'll see if I can talk to him.
我去跟他谈谈
The first thing I do when I get back
我回去第一件事就要订餐厅
is book a table at Wilton's  a private room.
一间贵宾室  ,
No bloody crowds.
没人打扰
Two pints of stout, please, guvner!
我要两品脱黑啤酒
Ha! Not long now, Harry!
我们很快就能回去了
Not long now!
很快
Trench.
崔屈
Please, Trench, get up. Trench, come on.
崔屈  ,  快起来
You escape today. Take the dead bodies to the pit
今天让你逃  ,  把尸体抬走
This man is dying. He paid me to release you
他快死了,  他付我钱放你走
lf you don't want to go, rot with him!
你不走就跟他一起死吧
What about you?
怎么样 ?
Food, please  Master
食物 求求你
I have some money.
我有钱
Money's no good for me.
钱没有用
I can't bribe the guards anymore.
我无法收买守卫
I have nothing left to lose
我虽置诸死地
nothing left to live for
却再没有活下去的理由
but still, I'm frightened.
我依然恐惧
Fear always remains.
恐惧永远不会消失
Pray for me, Abou.
为我祷告
Take as long as you like.
祷告多久都行
I don't walk too proudly now.
我不再感到自傲了
Stop.
e瞎说
Have some food.
吃点东西
You're looking better.
你的脸色好多了
You may not feel it, but you look it.
是真的
When I get better, will I look as bad as you?
我好了会跟你一样丑吗 ?
We'll get you through this, Trench.
我会帮你熬下去
I don't want to get through this, Harry.
我不想熬下去
I don't think I can take it anymore.
我已经受够了
I had a visitor today.
我今天有访客
He brought us a gift.
他带了礼物
The poison will take a few hours to work.
毒药几小时后生效
You won't feel any pain.
你一点都不会痛
That'll make a change.
那就好了
Careful.
小心
I didn't mean to be a pig about it.
我不是怕死哦
How about we give them one last night of hell?
今晚就给他们好看吧
I'll drink to that!
好极了
Make sure they're dead and throw them into the pit
他们死了就丢进坑里
The British prisoners are dead
英国 囚犯死了
Both of them?
两个都死了?
Yes
对
On the same day?
在同一天 ?
怎么会在同一天 ?
ldiot
白痴
Oh, Trench.
崔屈
I can't feel anything in my legs.
我的脚没有感觉
The poison has paralyzed your body.
毒药令你全身麻痹  ,
It'll wear off soon.
很快会恢复
I thought it was supposed to kill me.
我以为喝了它就会死
Only for a while.
只有一下子
You mean, you knew?
你早就知道 ?
I couldn't be short-changed.
我并不确定
That's the last time I let you buy the drink.
以后我不会喝你请的酒
How many bullets?
剩几发子弹 ?
One.
一发
Better make it count.
瞄准一点
No.
不
I can't carry him.
我背不动他
You can.
你可以
Save my friend.
救我的朋友
把他救走
Look after your friend.
好好照顾你的朋友
What will you do now?
现在你要做什么 ?
Whatever God has chosen for me.
听从上帝的旨意
Do I look that bad?
我有这么惨吗 ?
Everyone said how  much you'd changed.
大家都说你变了很多
I didn't believe them.
我不相信他们的话
May I have it back?
可以还我吗 ?
That isn't why I came.
这不是我来的目 的
I'd still like it back.
我还是想要回来
I'm almost sorry to let it go.
我不太想还你
It's brought me a lot of luck  over these past few months.
在这几个月  它 已变成我的幸运符
Have you heard our news?
你知道我们的事吗 ?
Yes.
知道了
How is Jack?
杰克好吗 ?
I think he's happy.
我想他很快乐
Good.
那就好
He deserves to be.
那是他应得的
So do you.
你也一样
It will pass.
一切都会过去
You will meet someone soon.
你会认识别的女孩
Then you and her and Jack and I
然后你跟她  ,  我跟杰克
Yes.
对
will set up tea and chat politely
就会一起喝茶聊天
as if  as if nothing ever happened with us before.
把一切都忘掉
That won't happen, Ethne.
我忘不了
It has to happen.
你一定要忘掉
It has to because I love you
因为我爱你
Harry.
哈利
I love you and I can't
我爱你  ,  但是我不能
I'm sorry.
对不起
Was that Ethne's carriage outside?
是艾瑟妮的马车 ?
She is giving me a ride to the station.
她要载我到车站
Why didn't she come out?
她怎么不上来 ?
I think she wanted to give us a minute or two alone.
她想让我们单独聊聊
Do we need a minute or two alone, Harry?
我们需要单独聊聊吗 ?
I came to thank you, Jack.
我是来谢你的
For what?
谢什么 ?
For standing by me.
谢谢你支持我
If you're talking about the feathers
羽毛那件事
I wasn't there.
我不在场
Willoughby told me you were.
威洛毕说你在
You don't owe me anything, Harry.
你并没有欠我什么
The wedding isn't for another month.
婚礼下个月 举行
Ethne is free to make up her own mind.
艾瑟妮有权改变心意
She's made up her mind.
她的心意已决
You should trust her judgment.
你应该相信她的决定
To Castleton and all the others we left behind.
敬卡索顿和其他弟兄
Indeed.
是的
You remember the first time we led a cavalry charge in public?
记得我们第一次骑兵表演吗 ?
Yes, I do, Jack.
当然  ,
You wiped the floor with me.
你跟我冲过头
I believe most of my horses ended up in the bandstand.
我的马冲上乐队指挥台
Yes, I did, and  yes, they did.
是啊 是啊  ,  真好笑
Ethne was there  watching.
艾瑟妮也在场 观看
Yes, I remember.
是啊  ,  我记得
You should.
你必定记得
You're the only one she danced with.
她只跟你跳舞
I've never been so jealous.
我嫉妒得不得了
I wanted to prove to her that I was the better soldier.
我想证明我是最好的军人
Well, you always were the better soldier, Jack.
你一向都是最好的军人
Yes, of course, but
当然了,  但是
She was the first person I looked for in the crowd
我第一眼就看着她
and she was staring at you.
她却凝望着你
Everyone else
大家都在为我鼓掌
was applauding me
and she was staring at you.
但她眼里却只有你
Nothing's changed.
始终如一
She's beautiful
她很美
isn't she?
对吧 ?
Yes, she is.
没错
You may be lost  but you are not forgotten.
虽然你们壮烈牺牲 却没有被遗忘
For those who have journeyed far
每一个远征沙场的军人
to fight in foreign lands
他们最大的安慰
know that the soldier's greatest comfort
就是身边
is to have his friends close at hand.
有好友相伴
Welcome home, Harry.
欢迎回家  ,  哈利
Thank you, sir.
谢谢
In the heat of battle
在浴血肉搏的战场
it ceases to be an idea
for which we fight
我们不再是
or a flag.
为国家而战
Rather
是为
we fight for the man on our left
生死与共的同胞而战
and we fight for the man on our right
为前仆后继的同胞而战
and when armies have scattered
当将士埋骨沙场
and when the empires fall away
当帝国倾颓蒙尘
all that remains is the memory of those precious moments
我们仍 拥有永志铭心的 回忆
we spent side by side.
以及拚肩作战的情谊
Forgive me.
原谅我
I did you a great wrong.
当时那么对你
There is nothing to forgive.
不要再说原谅了
Yes, there is.
当然要  ,
I should've stood by you, Harry.
我应该支持你
I should've understood.
我应该了解你的苦衷
I used to be so sure about everything.
我曾经坚信一切
We both were, Ethne.
我们都有过
And now?
现在呢 ?
And now
现在
Well  well, now I have no choice, Ethne.
我 我别无选择  ,
God put you in my way.
这是上帝的旨意